Guide to the Irving J. Lewis Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Irving J. Lewis papers
1968-1989
MS 1583
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12
(12 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence and files on teaching, presentations, the book The Sick Citadel, and federal government service which document Irving J. Lewis's career in health services.
Lewis, Irving J.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Irving J. Lewis, 1990.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Irving J. Lewis was born on July 9, 1918. He received his B.A. from Harvard in 1939, and his M.A. from the University of Chicago in 1940. After military service during World War II, Lewis began a long career in the federal government, working in the Office of Price Administration (1946-1947), the Department of State (1959-1960), the Federal Aviation Agency (1960), the U.S. Bureau of the Budget (1947-1957 and 1960-1968), and the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (1968-1970). After retiring from federal government service in 1970, Lewis was appointed a professor in the Department of Epidemiology and Social Medicine at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine in New York.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence and files on teaching, presentations, the book The Sick Citadel, and federal government service which document Irving J. Lewis's career in health services.
Medical policy -- United States; Medical care -- United States; Lewis, Irving J.
- Inventory, 1960s-1980s, undated; 12 linear feet (12 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Preliminary inventory by Carol King 1990 Feb
  Received from: Irving J. Lewis, 1990 Jan 15
  - Coalition for Medical Liability Reform
    - Alliance of American Insurers, undated (Box 1)
    - American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists, 1984-1987 (Box 1)
    - American Medical Association (AMA), medical malpractice studies, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Budget and contributions, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - Contracts, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Council of Catholic Hospitals, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Court opinions, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Executive committee, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - General correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
    - Health maintenance organizations (HMO), 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - Hospital Underwriter's Mutual Insurance Company, 1985 (Box 1)
    - LeBoeuf, Lamb, Leiby and MacRae, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - Lobbyist annual statement, 1984-1988 (Box 1)
    - Membership: Agreements, organizations, lists (3 folders), 1983-1990 (Box 1)
    - New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry, 1986 (Box 1)
    - 1986 mandated study (Box 1)
    - New York State Legislature, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - New York State Senate, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - News of New York, Liability Hotline - Medical Society of the State of New York, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Proposed, new legislation, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Rand Corporation, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Rice and Conway, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Senate Minority Task Force on Medical Malpractice, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Albany Legislative Day, 1986 May 21 (Box 1)
    - Coalition meetings, 1983 December 9-1989 November 10 (Box 1)
    - Coalition chronological files (correspondence), 1984-1988 (Box 1)
    - ND (Neurological Deficit infants) study by Swan Management Consultants, Inc., 1987-1988 (Box 2)
    - Report of the Special Advisory Panel on Medical Malpractice, State of New York, 1976 January (Box 2)
    - "The Harvard No-Fault Project: A Critique," by Maxwell J. Mehlman, interim and final reports, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - Legislation pertaining to neurologically impaired infant compensation bill, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - Coalition legislative program, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Neurological deficit study, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
    - Florida legislation, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
    - A Balanced Prescription for Change, report of the New York State Insurance Department on Medical Malpractice, 1988 April 1 (Box 2)
    - Draft bill and memorandum on medical malpractice, State of New York, executive chamber, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Malpractice file, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Resignation of Irving Lewis as Chairman of the New York Medical Liability Reform Coalition, 1989 (Box 2)
    - A Proposed Alternative to the Oct Civil Justice System for Resolving Medical Liability Disputes: A Fault-Based Administrative System, American Medical Association (AMA)/Specialty Society Medical Liability Project, 1987 October (Box 2)
    - Correspondence - general (Box 2)
    - A - misc (Box 3)
    - Albert Einstein College of Medicine (AECOM) of Yeshiva University, health lectures and curriculum development materials pertaining to community health, 1970s (Box 3)
    - Preferred Provider Organizations: The California Experiment, by Joan B. Trauner, 1983 August (Box 3)
    - AECOM, long range planning, 1983-1985 (Box 3)
    - AECOM Student Survey, 1987 (Box 3)
    - The American Journal of Public Health, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Association for Health Services Research, 1983-1985 (Box 3)
    - Association of Academic Health Centers (A.A.H.C), 1981 (Box 3)
    - B (Box 3)
    - Hermann Biggs Society, 1973-1979, 1980, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
    - Bronx Municipal Health Center, 1974 (Box 3)
    - Bronx planning, 1973 (Box 3)
    - Budgeting for Development and Improvement of Health Resources, memorandum, 1970 (Box 3)
    - C - general, 1976-1978, 1981-1986 (Box 3)
    - Center for Law and Health, Yeshiva University, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Center for Law and Health, Core group meeting on malpractice, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Cherkasky, Martin, Dr., 1971, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Commonwealth Fund, 1972-1974, 1981-1985 (Box 3)
    - Commonwealth Fund and the Academic Health Center (AHC) project, 1980s (Box 3)
    - Community Council of Greater New York, 1983, undated (Box 3)
    - Community Health, Dept. of, YU, 1971-1973, 1982 (Box 3)
    - D - general (Box 3)
    - Department of Epidemiology and Social Medicine (AECOM), 1983-1985 (Box 3)
      - Dept. program review, curriculum review (Box 3)
      - Appointments and promotions, 1984-1986 (Box 3)
      - Annual report, AIDS, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
      - Health policy, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
      - long-range curriculum planning, curriculum review, dept. program review (Box 3)
    - E - General, 1975-1977, 1981-1986 (Box 3)
    - F - General, 1974-1975, 1977, 1980-1986 (Box 3)
    - Fein, Rashi, 1971, 1973-1976, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
    - French trip, 1983 September (Box 3)
    - Friedman, Ephraim, 1975, 1977, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Fuller, Carol, 1989 (Box 3)
    - "Future Directions in Health Care: A New Public Policy," conference, New York City, 1977 February 15-16 (Box 3)
    - G - General, 1975-1977, 1981-1986 (Box 3)
    - H - General, 1981-1983, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Health Maintenance Organizations, Edward M. Kennedy letter, 1970-1972 (Box 3)
    - I - General, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
    - Institute of Medicine/National Academy of Sciences (IOM/NAS), 1971, 1976, 1978, 1981, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
    - IOM/NAS - Annual Meeting on AIDS, 1986 (Box 3)
    - AIDS BOOK, by Eve Nichols, based on presentations at IOM annual meeting, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Drafts and reviews of AIDS BOOK, 1986 (Box 3)
    - J - General, 1974, 1977-1978, 1981-1983, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Jaffé, Ernst R., 1972, 1974, 1984, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Johns Hopkins University Press, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
    - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, 1971-1974, 1981-1985, undated (Box 3)
    - K - General, 1971, 1975-1978, 1983, undated (Box 4)
    - Henry J. Kaiser Family Foundation, 1983 (Box 4)
    - L - General, 1982-1986 (Box 4)
    - Lectures, Columbia, NYU, Princeton and other schools, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
    - Lee, Philip R., 1983-1986 (Box 4)
    - Lombardi, Tarky, Jr., 1983, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Hospital Advisory Council to Senate Health Committee, Tarky Lombardi, Jr., 1976, undated (Box 4)
    - M - General, 1975-1984, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Medical malpractice correspondence, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1985, 1987 (Box 4)
    - N - General, 1975, 1981-1984 (Box 4)
    - National Board of Medical Examiners, 1984-1986 (Box 4)
    - National Center for Health Services Research, statement recommending enactment of H. R. 11316, 1976 (Box 4)
    - National Health Insurance (NHI), comparative analyses, 1970-1973, undated (Box 4)
    - NHI, family health insurance plan, 1971 (Box 4)
    - "The New Federalism: An Address and Statement," by Richard M. Nixon, with accompanying material, 1969 August (Box 4)
    - New York Academy of Medicine, 1978-1986 (Box 4)
    - New York Academy of Medicine, annual health conference, 1985 (Box 4)
    - New York Academy of Medicine, committee on medicine in society, 1981-1983 1985, 1987 (Box 4)
    - "The Role of Academic Medicine in Patient Education," New York Academy of Medicine, 1983 June 6-7 (Box 4)
    - New York City Health and Hospitals Corporation, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
    - New York State Commission on Graduate Medical Education, 1984-1987 (Box 4)
    - "Evaluation of the Process and Standards Used in Assessing the Qualifications of Foreign Medical Students for Clinical Training and Licensure in New York State", 1986 March (Box 4)
    - New York State Dept. of Health. Office of Professional Medical Conduct, 1986-1987 (Box 4)
    - Office of Technology Assessment (OTA), Diagnostic and Predictive Medical Tests Advisory Panel, 1986-1987 (Box 4)
    - OTA, health oversight panel, 1986-1988 (Box 4)
    - OTA, travel expenses of I. J. Lewis, 1985, 1987 (Box 4)
    - P - General, 1970s, 1980-1986 (Box 4)
    - Peer Review Program, New York State Medicare, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Q - General, 1985 (Box 4)
    - R, 1981-1987 (Box 4)
    - S, 1973-1979, 1981, 1983-1986 (Box 4)
    - Sheps, Cecil G., 1978, 1987 (Box 4)
    - T, 1976-1977, 1981, 1983-1985 (Box 4)
    - Terenzio, Joseph V., 1977-1978 (Box 4)
    - U, 1972 (Box 4)
    - United Hospital Fund of New York, grant project, 1973, 1976-1978, 1983-1986 (Box 4)
    - V, 1978-1979, 1983-1987 (Box 4)
    - W, 1974-1978, 1981-1984 (Box 4)
    - Weiss, Jeffrey H., 1979, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
    - XYZ, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Grant proposals, 1971-1977
    - "Area Health Education Centers" (AHEC) (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Grant request: "Einstein Health Services Research Center" (2 folders), 1970-1971, undated (Box 4)
    - Application for a Planning and Program Development Grant Under the "Comprehensive Health Manpower Training Act of 1971," Albert Einstein College of Medicine at Yeshiva University (Box 5)
    - Grant request: "Institute for Health Policy Development and Administration", 1972-1973, undated (Box 5)
    - Grant request: "Health Services - Politics, Public Policy and Accountability", 1973 (Box 5)
    - "The Feasibility of Developing a Children and Youth Project into a Health Maintenance Organization (HMO)," report, 1972 October (Box 5)
    - Technical proposal, Area Health Education Center Program, AHEC Program, 1977 August (Box 5)
    - Technical proposal (revised), AHEC Program, 1977 September (Box 5)
    - Business proposal (revised), AHEC Program, 1977 September (Box 5)
    - Journal of Medical Education, vol. 45, no. 12, 1970 December (Box 5)
    - "Health Professions Educational Assistance Act of 1976 (PL 94-484), HEW, 1978 January 30 (Box 5)
    - "A Report on the National AHEC Program," Public Health Reports, vol. 92, no. 2, 1977 April (Box 5)
  - Presentations and writings
    - "A Non-Professional Look at Regional Medical Programs", 1968 January 19 (Box 5)
    - "Some Reflections on Politics and Administration in Social Change", 1968 May 1 (Box 5)
    - "Remarks," Health Statistics Developmental Laboratory, Research Triangle Park, N.C., 1968 October 11 (Box 5)
    - "Society's Developing Needs and Government's Response to Them", 1968 October 17 (Box 5)
    - "Health Care and Health Care Insurance: Some Imperatives for the Future", 1968 October 30 (Box 5)
    - "Keynote Address," Regional Conference on Medical Costs, Denver, Colorado, 1968 November 19 (Box 5)
    - "Science and Health Care: the Political Problem", 1968 November 25 (Box 5)
    - "Address," Association of State and Territorial Health Officers (ASTHO), 1968 December 10 (Box 5)
    - "A Proposed Memphis Medical Center Master Plan," Mid-South Medical Center Council, Memphis, 1969 February (Box 5)
    - "Toward the Quality of Living", 1969 April 28 (Box 5)
    - "Health Care: Political Decisions and the Quality of the American Life", 1969 May 14-16 (Box 5)
    - "Financing and Delivery of Health Care - A Governmental View", 1969 May 21 (Box 5)
    - "Medicine in the Ghettos," conference, 1969 June 20-22 (Box 5)
    - "A Report on the Health of the Nation's Health Care System," by R. H. Finch and R. O. Egeberg, 1969 July 10 (Box 5)
    - "Program Priorities in Society", 1969 November 5 (Box 5)
    - Health Care in the 1970s - A Strategy for Change," HEW task force on Medicaid, 1969 December 12 (Box 5)
    - "Toward a Health Care Strategy", 1970 January 26 (Box 5)
    - "Health Care: The Political Setting", 1970 January 30 (Box 5)
    - "The Health Care Crisis - A Strategy for Change", 1970 March 17 (Box 5)
    - "Federal Health Programs - An Inventory", 1970 March 20 (Box 5)
    - "The National Health Scene", 1970 April 20-29 (Box 5)
    - "Delivery of Health Care in the 1970s", 1970 April 23 (Box 5)
    - The Health of Americans, edited by Boisfeuillet Jones, Thirty-seventh American Assembly report, 1970 April 23-26 (Box 5)
    - Ross Conference on the Future of Child Health Services, 1970 December (Box 5)
    - "The National Nutrition Survey - Viewpoint of a Public Administrator", 1971 October 12 (Box 5)
    - "Political Priorities and Controls: Implications for Medical Schools" (2 folders), 1972 April (Box 5)
    - Medical Care Seminar, Johns Hopkins University, 1972 September (Box 5)
    - "Is There a Future for Family Medicine?" Bat-Sheva Seminar in Health Administration and Health Economics (2 folders), 1972-1973 (Box 5)
    - New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University, fall course "Union Stake in Health Planning", 1973 (Box 5)
    - "The 1974 U. S. Budget - Past, Present, and Future", 1973 (Box 6)
    - "The Federal Health Budget Outlook", 1973 April 12 (Box 6)
    - "Experiences in Health Planning in the United States," by William Glaser, 1973 June 4-6 (Box 6)
    - "Prospects for Federal Support of Biomedical Research", 1973 June 15 (Box 6)
    - Federal Support of Biomedical Research and Medical Education", 1973 December (Box 6)
    - Medical Care Seminar, annual conference, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - "The Federal Health Investment: The Poor and Inflation", 1974 October (Box 6)
    - "The Impact of National Health Insurance," notes, 1975 April (Box 6)
    - "Resource Allocation: A Setting for Planning and National Health Insurance", 1975 November (Box 6)
    - "The 1977 U. S. Budget: A Time for Choice?", 1976 April (Box 6)
    - "The Number and Specialty Distribution of Foreign Medical Graduate House Staff in New York City Teaching Hospitals", 1978 June (Box 6)
    - "Quality Assurance and Health Care Policy", 1978 September 9 (Box 6)
    - Conference on Ethics and Health Cost Containment, 1978 October 4 (Box 6)
    - "Medical Manpower Needs: The Case of FMGs (foreign medical graduates)," by I. J. Lewis with others, 1978 October 16 (Box 6)
    - "Control of Health Care Costs: Freedom, Justice, and the Political Order" (2 folders), 1978-1980 (Box 6)
    - Book review by I. J. Lewis of The Malpractitioners, by John Guinther, 1979 (Box 6)
    - "The Myth of Quality Assurance and Health Care Policy", 1979 April 10 (Box 6)
    - Rotary Club speech, 1980 April 2 (Box 6)
    - "Academic Health Centers in the Service of Society", 1980 October 1-4 (Box 6)
    - Commentary on the paper of Dr. Rashi Fein, "The Economics of Medical Care", 1981 May (Box 6)
    - Book review by I. J. Lewis of Unequal Care - A Case Study of Interorganizational Relations in Health Care, by Murray Milner, Jr., 1981 June 26 (Box 6)
    - "The McGill Panel Revisited", 1981 October 19 (Box 6)
    - "AMC and the Public Interest," Biggs Society, 1981 December 10 (Box 6)
    - "Evolution of Federal Policy on Access to Health Care, 1965-1980" (2 folders), 1982 April 29-30 (Box 6)
    - New York Business Group on Health, Inc., 1983 (Box 6)
    - "Liberty, Equality, and Equity", 1983 April 15 (Box 6)
    - Bronx-Lebanon Grand Rounds, 1983 December 14 (Box 6)
    - "The Sick Citadel: A View of Academic Medical Centers", 1983 May 24 (Box 6)
    - Book review by I. J. Lewis of Biomedical Institutions, Biomedical Funding, and Public Policy, ed. by H. H. Gudenberg, 1984 (Box 6)
    - "UHF," United Hospital Fund, 1984 February (Box 6)
    - "A Commentary on Current Health Policy Dilemmas", 1984 April 23 (Box 6)
    - "Fiscal Crisis and the Academic Medical Center", 1984 May 27 (Box 6)
    - "The Context for Medical School Planning: General Politico/Economic Influences", 1985 (Box 6)
    - "A Commentary on the Health Policy Scene", 1985 February (Box 6)
    - Book review by I. J. Lewis of From Hierarchy to Competition in Health Services: an Alternative to Relman and Starr, by D. M. Fox, 1985 April (Box 6)
    - "Welcoming remarks," N. Y. Academy of Medicine, Annual Health Conference, 1985 May 2-3 (Box 7)
    - "Medical Malpractice: Paralysis or Solution in the Political Process", 1985 May 7 (Box 7)
    - New York Academy presentation - medical malpractice, 1986 February 24 (Box 7)
    - American Arbitration Assoc. presentation - medical malpractice, 1986 April (Box 7)
    - United Hospital Fund (UHF), 1986 May (Box 7)
    - County Medical Society, notes, 1986 March 5 (Box 7)
  - Unpublished reports and articles
    - Materials pertaining to Swedish and English health and social services used in preparation of report, "A Visit to England and Sweden," WHO Fellowship, 1977 October (Box 7)
    - Reports pertaining to academic medicine in the United Kingdom, 1970s-1980s (Box 7)
    - "Report of the President's Task Force on Government Reorganization", 1964 November 6 (Box 7)
    - "Report of the President's Task Force on Education", 1964 November 14 (Box 7)
    - Unpublished reports and articles (Box 7)
    - "Report of the Committee on Chronic Kidney Disease," University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 1967 September (Box 7)
    - The Godkin Lectures (I-III), by J. W. Gardner, 1969 March (Box 7)
    - Conference of Coordinators and Chairmen of Regional Advisory Groups of Regional Medical Programs, 1969 September (Box 7)
    - "Address," by R. M. Ball, Commissioner of Social Security, 1969 November (Box 7)
    - "The Academic Health Center and Health Care Delivery: Organizational Patterns to Meet New Responsibilities," by J. Evans, 1970 November (Box 7)
    - "The Scientific and Educational Basis for Medical Care," by I. L. Bennett, 1970 December (Box 7)
    - "Resources for Health Care," by W, D. Carey, 1971 March (Box 7)
    - "Social Security: Universal or Selective?" by W. J. Cohen, 1971 April (Box 7)
    - "Technology and Health Care Systems in the 1980s," by M, F. Collen, 1972 January (Box 7)
    - "Health Care Policy Issues in the '70s," by B. A. Myers, 1972 August (Box 7)
    - Agenda for 2000 A.D. -- Need for Systematic Anticipation, address by Warren Burger, 1976 April (Box 7)
    - "Technology Assessment: Opportunities and Obstacles, by S. R. Arnstein, 1976 May (Box 7)
    - "Medical Technology," National Center for Health Services Research (NCHSR), 1979 September (Box 7)
    - "Planning for National Health Insurance," by W.J. Cohen, 1979 November (Box 7)
    - National Center for Health Care Technology, 1980-1981, undated (Box 7)
    - "Policy Analysis for Federal Biomedical Research," by A.P. Williams, R.A. Rettig and others, 1976 March (Box 7)
    - "The Policy Debate on Patient Care Financing for Victims of End-Stage Renal Disease," by R. A. Rettig, 1976 fall (Box 7)
    - "End-Stage Renal Disease and the Cost of Medical Technology," by R. A. Rettig, 1977 October (Box 7)
    - "The Federal Government and Medical Technology: Crossing Policy and Management Thresholds," by R. A. Rettig, 1979 August (Box 7)
    - "The Politics of Health Cost Containment: End-Stage Renal Disease," by R.A. Rettig, 1980 January-February (Box 7)
    - "The Cost Effects of Improved Kidney Transplantation," by R. A. Rettig, 1984 February (Box 7)
    - Graduate Medical Education National Advisory Committee (GMENAC) (2 folders), 1978-1981 (Box 7)
    - "Public Policy and the Academic Medical Center," prospectus and outline, 1979 (Box 7)
    - New York Academy of Medicine conference, 1980 (Box 7)
    - "Reflections on Academic Health Centers," by R. E. Ebert, 1980 (Box 7)
  - The Sick Citadel, research and correspondence files
    - Op-Ed Page, New York Times, submissions, 1982-1983 (Box 8)
    - Book reviews by others of The Sick Citadel: The American Academic Medical Center and the Public Interest, by I. J. Lewis and C. G. Sheps (3 folders), 1980s (Box 8)
    - James A. Hamilton Hospital Administrators Book Award, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
    - Mailing list, complimentary copies soliciting comments re: The Sick Citadel (2 folders), 1982-1984 (Box 8)
    - The Commonwealth Fund, Margaret E. Mahoney, President, 1983-1984 (Box 8)
    - "Public Policy and the Academic Medical Center," by I. J. Lewis, The Commonwealth Fund Book Program Grant-in-Aid Request, 1979 (Box 8)
    - Lewis and Sheps, possible new project involving a study of community-based medical schools (2 folders), 1985 (Box 8)
    - Cecil G. Sheps, correspondence (2 folders), 1984-1986 (Box 8)
    - Catalog of tape transcripts, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Interview subject matter, index, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Interview tapes Box #1, Washington, Mt. Sinai, North Carolina, Duke, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Interview tapes Box #2, Florida, UCLA, Mayo, Johns Hopkins, Heyssel, Ebert notes, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Interview tapes Box #3, New Jersey, Dallas, Chicago, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Interview tapes Box #4, Michigan, Frederickson, New York, Richard Berman, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Notes for projected project on state and federal relationships, 1984-1985 (Box 9)
  - Selected Syllabi, Albert Einstein College of Medicine
    - "The Politics and Economics of Health and Medicine: Who Gets What, When, and How", 1982 spring (Box 9)
    - "The Health Care System: Organization, Financing, Politics, and Issues", 1983 fall (Box 9)
    - "Health Care in a Changing Community", 1983 winter (Box 9)
    - "The Health Care System: Organization and Emerging Policy Issues and Developments", 1984 fall (Box 9)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW)
    - Health Services and Mental Health Administration (HSMHA), organization, 1968 (Box 9)
    - HSMHA Legislative Strategy report, 1969 (Box 9)
    - "Organization and Delivery of Health Services: Forward Plans 1971-1975," report to the Health Task Force by the Planning Team, 1969 (Box 9)
    - Untitled report of 1968 Task Force (Box 9)
    - Partnership for Health -- Comprehensive Health Planning, report, 1969 (Box 9)
    - "FY 1971 to 1875, Health Planning Team Organization and Delivery Only," report, 1969 (Box 9)
    - "Health Services Improvement Act Hill-Burton Amendments, 1970 (Box 9)
    - "Health Services Improvement Act,' (s.3344; H. R. 15960), report (2 binders), 1970 (Box 10)
    - "Report on Health Needs," Health Services Delivery Coordinating Committee, 1970 August 22 (Box 10)
    - "HSMHA information materials," report, 1970 (Box 10)
    - "HSMHA Legislative Proposals," report, 1969 (Box 10)
    - "Chronic Disease Programs," report, 1969 (Box 10)
    - "The Secretary's Regional Conference on Health Care Costs", 1968 November (Box 10)
    - "A State Perspective on the Nation's Health," proceedings, 1968 December (Box 10)
  - Washington files, Late 1960s-1970s, undated (Box 11)
    - Personal history (Box 11)
    - Personal correspondence, unsorted (Box 11)
    - Photographs, 1960s, 1980s (Box 11)
    - Budget